Curriculum Vitae/Resume

Kyogo Kanazawa

Revised: September 26, 2024

Current Positions

Lecturer (tenure-track), Graduate School of International Social Sciences and Department of Economics, Yokohama National University, April 2024 - present.

Guest Researcher, Center for Research and Education in Program Evaluation (CREPE), The University of Tokyo, April 2022 - present.

Contact Information

Graduate School of International Social Sciences, Yokohama National University. 79-4 Tokiwadai, Hodogaya-ku, Yokohama 240-8501, Japan.

Email: kanazawa.kyogo@gmail.com

Research Fields

Industrial Organization, Health Economics, Applied Microeconometrics.

Past Position

Researcher, Economic and Social Research Institute (ESRI), Cabinet Office, Government of Japan, April 2022 - March 2024.

Project Researcher, Department of Economics, The University of Tokyo, April 2019 - March 2022.

Education

Doctor of Philosophy in Economics, The University of Tokyo, April 2011 - March 2019 (on leave from April 2013 to March 2016, PhD awarded in January 2023).

Advisor: Hidehiko Ichimura

Master of Arts in Economics, The University of Tokyo, April 2009 - March 2011.

Advisor: Hidehiko Ichimura

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, Keio University, April 2005 - March 2009.

Advisor: Yasunari Tamada

Other Employment

Systems Engineer, Information Planning Co., April 2013 - March 2016.

Published/Accepted Papers

"Displacement Effects of Public Libraries," Journal of the Japanese and International Economies, 2022, Volume 66, 101219 (joint with Kohei Kawaguchi)

Working Papers

"Impact of Hospital Decision-making on Drug Markets: The Case of Biosimilars," ESRI Discussion Paper Series No.396, July 2024

"AI, Skill, and Productivity: The Case of Taxi Drivers," NBER Working Paper No. 30612, October 2022 (joint with Daiji Kawaguchi, Hitoshi Shigeoka, and Yasutora Watanabe), revise and resubmit at *Management Science*

"Quantifying Health Shocks Over the Life Cycle," RIETI Discussion Paper Series 18-E-014, March 2018 (joint with Taiyo Fukai and Hidehiko Ichimura)

Conference Presentations

- 2022 3rd Asian Workshop on Econometrics and Health Economics (poster session), reviewed, Matsushima, Miyagi, Japan.
- 2022 Summer Workshop on Economic Theory, invited, Otaru, Hokkaido, Japan.
- 2021 Asian and Australasian Society of Labour Economics 2021 Conference, reviewed, online.
- 2019 Japanese Economic Association Spring Meeting, reviewed, Musashi University, Tokyo, Japan.
- 2018 Japanese Economic Association Autumn Meeting (poster session), reviewed, Gakushuin University, Tokyo, Japan.
- 2018 The 45th Annual Conference of the European Association for Research in Industrial Economics, reviewed, Athens College, Psychiko, Greece.
- 2018 Summer Workshop on Economic Theory, invited, Otaru University of Commerce, Hokkaido, Japan.
- 2018 Japanese Economic Association Spring Meeting, reviewed, University of Hyogo, Hyogo, Japan.
- 2018 Junior Industrial Organization Workshop, reviewed, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.

Seminar Presentations

- 2023 Hitotsubashi University. Yokohama National University.
- 2022 Yokohama City University, online.
- 2020 Happy Hour Seminar, online.
- 2018 Keio University.

Professional Membership

Japanese Economic Association, April 2018 - present.

Referee Services

Japanese Economic Review

Teaching Experience

Selected Topics in econometrics (Graduate), Yokohama National University, Fall 2024. (scheduled)

Econometrics: Intermediate (Undergraduate), Yokohama National University, Fall 2024. (scheduled)

Econometrics (Graduate), Yokohama National University, Spring 2024.

Econometrics (Undergraduate), Yokohama National University, Spring 2024.

Microeconomics II (Graduate), Hosei University, Fall 2023.

Microeconomics I (Graduate), Hosei University, Spring 2023.

Calculus and Matrix Algebra / Calculus and Matrix Analysis (Undergraduate, Graduate), Osaka University, Spring 2023. (joint with Takeshi Murooka)

Teaching Assistant, Introduction to Program Evaluation (CREPE Lecture series), Center for Research and Education in Program Evaluation (CREPE) The University of Tokyo, Hidehiko Ichimura, February - May 2018.

Teaching Assistant, Econometrics (Graduate), The University of Tokyo, Hidehiko Ichimura, Spring 2012.

Teaching Assistant, Econometrics (Undergraduate), The University of Tokyo, Yoshihiro Yajima, Fall 2011.

Teaching Assistant, Contract Theory (Undergraduate), Keio University, Yasunari Tamada, Fall 2009.

Teaching Assistant, Contract Theory (Undergraduate), Keio University, Yasunari Tamada, Spring 2009.